<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homepage on Joonas Tuhkuri</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Homepage on Joonas Tuhkuri</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>/sections/aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/aboutme/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m an economist (PhD, MIT) and an Assistant Professor of Economics at Stockholm University. I&amp;rsquo;m also a Senior Fellow at Etla and affiliated with IZA.
My research focuses on technology, work, and psychology using novel large-scale data. My latest work documents that when firms adopted advanced technologies they increased employment—contrasting with common concerns about the future of work.
The media has featured my research widely, including in The Economist and Wired.</description></item><item><title/><link>/sections/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/contact/</guid><description>Email: joonas.tuhkuri@su.se
Tel: +358 400 239 818
Address:
Stockholm University
Department of Economics
106 91 Stockholm, Sweden</description></item><item><title/><link>/sections/data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/data/</guid><description>Projects
ETLAnow: Real-time unemployment forecasts based on Google search data. 2014–
Featured in The Washington Post, Bloomberg, Chicago Tribune, YLE News, HS, and widely in the global media.
Code
Occupation Codes: This package harmonizes Finnish occupation codes.
Industry Codes: This package harmonizes Finnish industry codes (2 and 3 digit levels).
County and Subregion Codes: This package harmonizes Finnish county codes into consistent subregions.</description></item><item><title/><link>/sections/media/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/media/</guid><description>The Economist: Economists are revising their views on robots and jobs, 2022.
The Economist: Leader: The world should welcome the rise of the robots, 2022.
Wired: Automation Isn&amp;rsquo;t the Biggest Threat to US Factory Jobs, 2022.
Bloomberg: Understanding Europe’s Economy in 100 Billion Google Searches, 2016.</description></item><item><title/><link>/sections/policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/policy/</guid><description>Policy Brief: New Evidence on the Effect of Technology on Employment and Skill Demand, ETLA Brief 108, 2022 (with J. Hirvonen and A. Stenhammar).
Forecasting Unemployment with Google Searches, ETLA Working Paper 35, 2016.
ETLAnow: A Model for Forecasting with Big Data, ETLA Report 54, 2016.
Big Data: Do Google Searches Predict Unemployment?, University of Helsinki, 2015.
Big Data: Google Searches Predict Unemployment in Finland, ETLA Report 31, 2014.
International Sourcing in Finland and Sweden, ETLA B 275, 2017 (with H.</description></item></channel></rss>