<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homepage on Joonas Tuhkuri</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Homepage on Joonas Tuhkuri</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>/sections/aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/aboutme/</guid><description>I am an economist (PhD, MIT) and an Assistant Professor of Economics at Stockholm University from 2023. Currently, I am based in Berlin at the new Rockwool Foundation Berlin and the Berlin School of Economics.
My research focuses on technology, work, and psychology using novel large-scale data. My latest research documents that new technologies led to increases in employment, contrasting with the common concerns about the future of work. I previously created a real-time forecast ETLAnow that predicts unemployment using Google search data.</description></item><item><title/><link>/sections/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/contact/</guid><description>Email: joonas.tuhkuri@gmail.com
Tel: +358 400 239 818
Address: Department of Economics
Humboldt Universitat zu Berlin
Spandauer Strasse 1 10178 Berlin</description></item><item><title/><link>/sections/data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/data/</guid><description>Projects:
ETLAnow: Real-time unemployment forecasts based on Google search data. 2014–
Featured in: The Washington Post, Bloomberg, Chicago Tribune, and other global media.
Crosswalks:
Occupation Codes: This package harmonizes Finnish occupation codes.
Industry Codes: This package harmonizes Finnish industry codes (2 and 3 digit levels).
County and Subregion Codes: This package harmonizes Finnish county codes into consistent subregions.</description></item><item><title/><link>/sections/policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/policy/</guid><description>“International Sourcing in Finland and Sweden,” 2017, ETLA B Series 275 (with Hans Lööf, Petri Rouvinen et al.)
“ETLAnow: A Model for Forecasting with Big Data – Forecasting Unemployment with Google Searches in Europe,” 2016, ETLA Reports 54. Featured in: The Washington Post, Chicago Tribune, Bloomberg, YLE News, HS
“Globalization Threatens One Quarter of Finnish Employment,” ETLA Brief 46, Featured in: YLE News, HS
“Finland in global value chains,” 2016 (with Jyrki Ali-Yrkkö, Petri Rouvinen, and Pekka Sinko), Prime Minister’s Office Publications 11/2016.</description></item></channel></rss>